Guide to the David Lyons and Matthew Lyons Cornell divestment movement collection, 1976-1987.
Cornell divestment movement collection, 1976-1987
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
David Lyons and Matthew Lyons Cornell divestment movement collection, 1976-1987.
18-2-2541
David Lyons, 1935-
1 cubic ft.
Reports, legal documents, memos, articles, leaflets, posters, and other publications.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Reports; legal documents; memos; and articles, leaflets, posters, and other publications, all relating to the movement for Cornell divestment in South Africa.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Matthew Lyons (Cornell University Class of 1986) helped to organize and participated in the first divestment sit-ins at Cornell's Day Hall in April-May 1985, as well as the May 8, 1985 action, "Take It To the Straight." In the fall of 1985, he helped to coordinate the divestment movement's daily sit-ins and civil disobedience at Day Hall. David Lyons, Matthew's father, is professor of law and philosophy at Cornell University. He was part of the first group of Cornell faculty and staff to be arrested in the divestment sit-ins in April 1985. He helped to draft the principal Faculty and Staff Against Apartheid (FSAA) documents including "Why Cornell Should Divest" and the FSAA's reply to the Proxy Review Committee Report on divestment. He represented Shantytown residents within the Cornell judicial system with regard to their complaints against the central administration.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Reports; legal documents; memos; and articles, leaflets, posters, and other publications, all relating to the movement for Cornell divestment in South Africa.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Lyons, David, 1935-; Lyons, Matthew Nemiroff.; Cornell University--Students.; Cornell University--Faculty.
Subjects:
Student movements.; Students--Political activity.; Disinvestment.
Places:
United States--Foreign relations--South Africa.; South Africa--Economic conditions--1961-1991.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- CIA protests, Spring 1985 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- SADC (South Africa Divestment Coalition) report, 1983, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Trustee and Johnson Wax investment policies, 1976-1985 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Trustee conflicts of interest re: investment policy (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Articles on divestment and divestiture - non-Cornell sources (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Articles on South Africa - non-Cornell sources (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Harvard alumni divestment work (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Cornell divestment leaflets, memos, etc., Apr.-June 1985 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Spring 1985 cases - City Court (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Spring 1985 cases - Cornell judicial system (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Faculty and Staff Against Apartheid (FSAA), Spring 1985 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Shantytown civil litigation, Spring 1985 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Cornell Review (anti-divestment), May 1985 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Divestment Convocation, June 1985 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Ithaca Journal reporting protest, June 1985 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Divestment legal analysis, Summer 1985 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Eduation Against Oppression (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Cornell divestment leaflets, memos, Summer, Fall 1985 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- FSAA, Summer, Fall 1985 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Faculty referendum on divestment, May-Sept. 1985 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- New York Supreme Court cases, Fall 1985 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Fall 1985 cases - Cornell judicial system (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Proxy Review Committee report and discussion/replies, Fall 1985-Jan. 1986 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Non-divestment activism related to divestment movement, 1985-1986 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Spring 1986 cases - Cornell judicial system (Box 1, Folder 25)
- FSAA, Spring 1986 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Cornell Divestment and Anti-Racism Coalition leaflets, memos, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Cornell Judicial System Cases, Fall 1986 (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Arts Faculty Resolution 10/86 / FSAA, Fall 1986 (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Spring 1987 cases - Cornell judicial system (Box 1, Folder 30)
- Humor (Box 1, Folder 31)
- Leftist student publications, 1985-1987 (Box 1, Folder 32)
- FSAA, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 33)
- UAW and faculty/student support, 1985-1987 (Box 1, Folder 34)
- Free speech and Cornell photo policy, 1977-1985 (Box 1, Folder 35)
- Proposed Campus Code changes (RAMPO), June-late 1985 (Box 1, Folder 36)
- New Campus Code, etc. instituted (Box 1, Folder 37)
- Free Speech Commission, 1986-1987 (Box 1, Folder 38)
- Shantytown documents (Box 1, Folder 39)
- Drafts of shantytown complaints, May 1985 (Box 1, Folder 40)
- Original shantytown complaints vs. Cornell, May-June 1985 (Box 1, Folder 41)
- Prior cases relevant to shantytown hearings (Cornell judicial system) (Box 1, Folder 42)
- Amended shantytown complaints, June 1985 (Box 1, Folder 43)
- Exchange of memos re: shantytown complaints, Summer 1985 (Box 1, Folder 44)
- Shantytown appeal to Cornell Hearing Board (Box 1, Folder 45)
- Shantytown appeal to Cornell Review Board (Box 1, Folder 46)
- Divestment poster, Spring 1985 (Box 1, Folder 47)